https://slama.dev/comeback/
https://slama.dev/comeback/
Ivuska, you won't believe what happened to me.
Ivuško, ty si nevěříš, co se mi stalo.
Did your kefir ferment?
Zkvasil ti kefír?
Don't be silly.
Nebuď buvatá.
Sorry.
Promiň.
Hey, you don't even remember Kvetos from the flea market, do you?
He, když už se nepamatuješ Květoše z trejdušce, viď?
Kvetos from the flea market?
Z trejdu Květoše?
A crook.
Zvolár.
Is that who you got this drunk with?
To s ním ses takhle opil?
I thought you weren't talking to him.
Já myslela, že se s ním nebavíš.
I'm not, normally.
Nebavím po jevači tovejta.
But today I had a good time.
Ale dneska jsem se bavil.
I can see that.
To vidím.
He kept bragging like crazy.
Jsem furt vytahoval jak v Šandy.
But I showed him.
Ale já jsem mu to nandal.
I hope you weren't bragging too.
Doufám, že ses taky nevytahoval.
I had to.
To jsem musel.
I couldn't exactly tell him the truth, that wouldn't work.
Přece jsem nemohl říct pravdu, to by nefungovalo.
Dad.
Tati.
Ivuska, he keeps showing off that he has the biggest construction company in the district and that Ruzena is the deputy mayor.
Ivuško, on se furt naparuje, že má největší stavební firmu ve okrese a že Růžena je místostarostka.
Ruzena?
Růžena?
Didn't she go to a special school?
Nechodila ona do zvláštní školy?
Exactly.
No právě.
So I just had to tell him.
Tak jsem mu to prostě říct musel.
And what exactly?
A co přesně?
That I'm the director of Metrostav.
Že jsem ředitel Metrostavu.
And Ozzak is a notary.
A Ozzák, že je notář.
And I lost my phone.
A ztratil jsem mobilu.
Maria, this is a mess.
Maria, to je průser.
Turn that off.
Tak tohle vypni.
What is it?
Co to je?
Something for nausea.
Něco proti zvracení.
Ozzak's recipe.
Ozzákův recept.
And what's in it?
A co v tom je?
If I told you, it would work the other way.
Kdybych ti to řekla, tak to bude fungovat obráceně.
Yuck!
Fuj!
I'd rather make some tea.
Podělám si radši čaj.
What about the phone?
Co ten mobil?
That's the least of my worries.
To je mě trápit nejmíň.
Oh God, I'm an idiot.
Panebože, já jsem idiot.
I promised him we'd come.
Slíbil jsem mu, že přijedeme.
He said he'd slaughter a pig.
Řekl, že zabije prase.
Great.
Fajn.
I've been wanting Ruzena's recipe for black cake anyway.
Stejně jsem chtěla od Růženy recept na černý dort.
Are you crazy?
Ty jsi se zbláznila?
How can we go after what I told him?
Copak to jde po tom, co jsem mu řekl?
Well then we just won't go.
No tak nikam nepojedem, no.
That won't work either.
A to taky nejde.
He'd say I'm scared of him.
Řekl by, že se ho bojím.
I don't know what you two have against each other.
Já nevím, co spolu vůbec máte.
I just can't stand how he's always showing off.
Prostě nesnáším, jak se furt vytahuje.
Like you don't do that.
Hlavně, že ty to neděláš.
But I'm glad you at least left me out of it.
Ale jsem ráda, že aspoň mě sis ušetřil.
You didn't?
Neušetřil?
You dance flamenco.
Tancuješ flamengo.
Competitively.
Závodně.
Sorry.
Promiň.
When he was showing me photos of little Kvetos at dance school, I couldn't help myself.
Když on jak mi ukazoval ty fotky malých Květoš z tanečních, tak jsem se neudržel.
Wonderful.
Výborně.
So I'll grab castanets, Ozzak will get glasses, and we'll head to Volary.
Tak já si vezmu kastaněty, Ozzák brejle a půjdem do Volar.
By metro.
Metrem.
Cut it out.
Nepřestaň.
Sarcasm won't help us.
Ironie nám nepomůže.
Wait.
Moment.
I don't have my phone.
Já nemám mobil.
Kvetos won't be able to reach me, he'll get offended, and we won't have to go to the pig slaughter.
Květoš si nedovolá, urazí se a my nebudeme muset na tu zabíjačku jezdit.
We're going to the pig slaughter!
Jedeme na zabíjačku!
How do you know about the pig slaughter?
Jak víš o zabíjačce?
Kvetos called.
Květoš volal.
You left your phone at my place.
Nechal sis u mě mobil.
This is bad, hey, Kvetos told me to my face that I'm a notary.
To je blbý, hej, že mi Květoš do očí řekl, že jsem notář.
So what?
No a co?
I just went along with it.
Nechal jsem ho při tom.
Everyone thinks that about you anyway, right?
Stejně si to všichni myslej, ne?
What is this?
Co to je?
Tea.
Čaj.
Linden.
Lipovej.
You wanted it.
Vždyť jsi to chtěl.
It's disgustingly sweet.
Vždyť je to hnusně přeslazený.
Maybe I put too much linden in?
Že bych tam toho lípu dala moc?
I'll just have water.
No já si dám raději vodu.
It's business.
Jsou kšefty.
Get out of here!
Se úplně vyprášej!
For God's sake, you stink.
Proboha, táhneš.
It's for the blood sausage soup.
To je na prdelačku.
I couldn't get one anywhere.
Nemohl jsem jí sehnat.
In the end, young Coufal and his buddies hauled it from work for a bottle.
Nakonec mi ji za flašku z práce přitáhl mladej Coufal s kámošema.
From work? He's only seven!
Jak z práce, vždyť je mu sedm?
Good thing they only gave him wine.
Ještě, že se mu dali jenom víno.
And where are you returning it?
A kam ty to vrátíš?
Blood sausage soup, he said.
Prdelačku, říkal.
Yeah, we're going to our cousin's for a pig slaughter.
Jo, jedeme k bratrancovi na zabíjačku.
We're not going.
Nejedeme.
I don't get it, why don't you want to go to the pig slaughter?
Já to nechápu, proč nechceš jet na zabíjačku?
It's complicated.
To je složitý.
It's simple.
Je to jednoduchý.
He told his cousin we're some fancy family and now he's afraid they'll find us out.
Nakecal mu, že jsme děsně nobel rodina a teď má strach, že nás odhalej.
Don't worry, bro, we can pull it off.
Neboj, brácha, to zvládnem.
And you think anyone's going to believe you're a notary?
A ty si myslíš, že ti někdo uvěří, že seš notář?
Oh well, I'll just drink a bit more than usual and then start screaming that I see white mice.
No bože, jen tak budu chlastat o něco víc než normálně a pak začnu řvát, že vidím bílý myši.
Don't be daft.
Ty nebuď blben.
Sausages don't just lie around on the street.
Jitrnice se neválej jen tak na ulici.
Well, I once found one like that.
No, já jsem takhle jednu našel.
It could be a terrible embarrassment.
Mohla by být z toho hrozná vostuda.
What embarrassment?
Jaká vostuda?
When I rinsed it off.
Když jsem si ji oplách.
You can't cheat your family just because you can't bluff a little.
Přece nebudeš šidit rodinu jenom proto, že neumíš trochu kecat.
I'm not cheating and I'm not bluffing.
Nešidím a nekecám.
I should have stood up to my brother.
Měl jsem bráchovi kousnout.
Come on, tell me how it tastes.
No řekni, jak ti chutná.
Ozzak, cut it out.
Ozzáku, nech toho.
You know he can't lie.
Vždyť víš, že neumí lhát.
Well, Kvetos, you'd actually bluff pretty well.
No, Květoš, že bys kecal docela slušně.
Director.
Řediteli.
Look, take that pot and go return it to those kids.
Hele, víš co, vem tu várnici a běž ji vrátit těm dětem.
Now?
Teď?
Do you know how heavy it is?
Víš, jak je těžká?
It's still full of tea.
Ještě je furt plná čaje.
If you're not up for it, I could help you out.
Tak jestli se na to necítíš, tak já bych ti mohla píchnout.
How exactly?
A jak jako?
I could maybe go with you guys.
No mohla bych jet třeba s váma.
As your spokesperson.
Jako tvoje mluvčí.
You wouldn't have to lie and I'd say everything for you.
Ty bys nemusel lhát a já bych řekla všechno za tebe.
Director.
Řediteli.
Pepita, listen, you can't come along as a spokesperson, that's completely absurd.
Pepito, poslouchej, nemůžeš se mnou dovolat jako mluvčí, teď je to úplně absurdní.
What's absurd is not getting anything from relatives.
Absurdní je z příbuzných nic nevyrazit.
Hi.
Ahoj.
Hi, mom.
Ahoj, mami.
What did great-aunt send me?
Co mi prateta posílá?
Nothing?
Nic?
She said she's not falling for these tricks anymore.
Říkala, že na tyhle triky už nenaletí.
What's wrong?
Co je?
Ivo, can we leave a Fidorka bar at your place?
Ivo, můžeme si u tebe nechat Fidorku?
A Fidorka bar?
Fidorku?
Why?
Proč?
We got it from great-aunt.
Dostali jsme ji od pratety.
I'm sorry, what?
Co prosím?
We agreed that whoever goes the longest without saying one letter gets to eat it.
Dohodli jsme se, že ji sní ten, kdo nejdýl nevysloví jedno písmeno.
And if we kept it at home, someone would eat it at night.
A kdybysme si ji nechali doma, tak by se v noci sní.
How dare you.
No dovol.
I'm hungry, man.
Já mám hlad, fé.
Yeah, last time you ate my pear.
Jo, minule jsi mi sežral hrušku.
Oh God.
Panebože.
Ivo, do you know which letter it is?
Ivo, víš, co je to za písmeno?
I think so.
Tuším.
Well, great then.
No tak skvěle.
R?
R?
Yeah.
No.
What if I gave you another Fidorka bar?
Co kdybych vám dala ještě jednu Fidorku?
Would you stop this?
Přestali byste s tím?
Great-aunt deliberately gave us just one to spark our competitiveness.
Prateta nám schválně dala jenom jednu, aby v nás probudila soutěživost.
Great idea, huh?
Skvělá nápad, co?
Grumbling's not allowed either.
Brblat se taky nesmí.
I don't want to risk it.
Nechci riskovat.
I'd like to see that.
To ti chci vidět.
When the teacher quizzes you tomorrow on the French Revolution.
Až tě zítra paní učitelka bude zkoušet z velký francouzský revoluce.
Damn it.
A sakra.
It's morning.
To je ráno.
Where did this come from?
Kde se to tu vzalo?
Ozzak left it for you.
To vám tu nechal Ozzák.
So you'd know.
Když budete vědět.
He really thinks that if he hangs a pig here, I'll go to the pig slaughter.
Tak on si snad myslí, že když mi tady pověsí prase, tak já na tu zabíjačku pojedu.
In that case, I don't understand why he tore down my poster of Tri Clunky yesterday.
V tom případě nechápu, proč mi včera strhnul ten plakát na tři člunky.
He hates Nohavica.
Nesnáší Nohavicu.
Hello?
Haló?
Yes, I'll pass you over.
Ano, předávám.
Pacovsky!
Pacovský!
Hey, Kvetos.
Je, Květoši.
Well, how do you think I feel, you know, we had a few drinks yesterday.
No, tak jak by mi bylo, to víš, včera jsme něco vypili.
Well, I went for a run this morning too, of course.
No, tak já jsem byl ráno taky samozřejmě běhat.
How far?
Kolik?
Only five kilometers, right?
Jenom pět kiláků, jo?
Well, there you go, it'll get even better.
No to vidíte, ještě půjde líp.
What woman?
Jaká ženská?
Oh, the phone's answered by my... secretary.
Jo, no telefony mi zvedá ta... sekretářka.
Well, you know, I wouldn't pick an ugly one.
No to víš, šeredu bych si nevybral.
Taking it easy?
Klídek?
No way, you know, the metro doesn't build itself.
No to ani náhodou, to víš, metro se samo nepostaví.
Yeah, hold on.
Jo, moment.
Xenie, stop standing around and take those invoices to accounting.
Xenie, nestůjte tady a odneste ty účty do účtárny.
Chop, chop, chop, chop, get out of my sight.
No, šup, šup, šup, šup, ať už vás tady nevidím.
Damn secretaries, they never do anything.
Zatracený sekretářky, nic nedělaj.
You have a secretary too?
Taky máš sekretářku?
Be glad you don't, she's nothing special.
No to buď rád, není o co stát.
And how's Ruzena?
A co Růžena?
She's heading to parliament.
Je do parlamentu.
Well of course, who else should be there but her?
No jasně, tak kdo jiný by tam měl být než ona?
Yeah, Kvetos, listen, about the pig slaughter.
Jo, Květoši, prosím tě, ta zabíjačka.
Look, I'm completely booked until June, completely, you know, and...
Hele, já to mám do června úplně plný, ale úplně, víš, a...
No, of course I'm not bragging.
Ne, no jasně, že jsem se nevytahoval.
I can take time off whenever I want.
No tak já si můžu udělat volno, kdy chci.
What?
Co?
Saturday, sure, no problem.
V sobotu, no klidně.
Sure.
Jasně.
Yeah, all three of us.
No, všichni tři.
Hold on.
Moment.
Xenie, what am I doing on Saturday?
Xenie, co dělám v sobotu?
Cancel the minister.
Tak toho ministra zrušte.
Ruzena will fire him after the elections anyway.
Stejně ho Růžena po volbách odvolá.
And call Iva and the doctor and tell them we're going to Volary on Saturday.
A brnkněte Ivě a panu doktorovi, že v sobotu jdeme do Volar.
Yeah, it's all set.
Jo, ale taky to je domluvený.
I'm so looking forward to it.
Já tak se těším.
Builder's honor.
Čestný stavařský.
See ya.
Tak čau.
Xenie.
Xenie.
Jesus Christ.
Ježíšmarja.
What just came over me?
Co to zase na mě vyjelo?
Oh, you men.
Ach, vy muži.
You were lying just like Zoran when he calls his brother.
Prášil jste úplně stejně jako Zoran, když si volá s bratrem.
The other day he even told him he bought an island.
Tuhle mu dokonce vykládal, že si koupil ostrov.
Well, that's really something.
No to je teda síla.
You know.
Víte.
Although it's really just a small island.
A přitom je to jen takový ostrůvek.
Bye!
Páce!
Bye.
Páce.
Coffee.
Kávo.
Well, thanks a lot.
Tak ti teda pěkně děkuju.
Sorry.
Promiň.
I was kept after school for two hours and all you say is sorry?
Dvě hodiny jsem byla po škole a ty promiň?
You know I'm not allowed to say that letter.
Teď víš, že nesmím vyslovit to písmeno.
Then don't help me at all.
Tak radši nenapovídej vůbec.
Sorry.
Promiň.
Everyone was laughing at me.
Teď se mi všichni smáli.
Because of you I said that the Jacobins "pampered" Louis the Sixteenth.
Kvůli tobě jsem řekla, že Jakobíny Ludvíka šestnáctýho popravili.
Shut up.
Sklapni.
I didn't tell you to say "pampered."
Já jsem ti nenapovídala popravili.
Because of your stupid game I got a failing grade.
Kvůli vaší debilní hře mám kouli.
I got a failing grade too.
Já jsem taky dostal kouli.
But in math.
Ale z matiky.
Because you still don't know how to divide fractions.
Protože ještě furt neumíš dělit zlomky.
And you don't even know they executed him.
A ty zas nevíš, že ho popravili.
You're still not ready?
Vy ještě nejste nachystaný?
Mom, couldn't we just go to dad's normally today?
Mami, nemohli bysme dneska za tátou jít normálně?
When he starts paying child support properly, then for all I care you don't have to go at all.
Až bude normálně platit alimenty, tak tam pro mě za mě nemusíte vůbec.
Ivo.
Ivo.
So you're going to the pig slaughter after all.
Tak vy prej nakonec na tu zabíjačku pojedete.
Dad maybe.
Otec možná.
Not Ozzak?
Ozzák ne?
He's been getting sick from grass.
Vždyť se mu dělá z trávy.
He thinks it'll clean out his stomach.
Myslí si, že mu to vyčistí žaludek.
I want to see how they'll react to a notary who vomits daisies.
To chci vidět, jak se tam budou tvářit na notáře, který zvrací sedmikrásky.
Such a show over a bit of headcheese, right?
Takový divadýlko kvůli troše prejtu, viď?
Exactly.
Právě.
So you're not going?
A ty teda nejedeš?
Am I crazy?
Jsem blázen?
Having to pretend I can do flamenco?
Abych tam především musela dělat, že umím flamenko?
Flamenco?
Flamenko?
Yeah.
No.
Oh, Ozzak told me you'd be playing the womanizer, that didn't make sense to me.
Aha, Ozzák mi říkal, že budeš dělat flamendra, to mi právě nebylo jasné.
Neither womanizer nor flamenco.
Ani flamendra, ani flamenko.
I'm not going anywhere.
Nikam nejedu.
You're right.
Máš recht.
One should maintain dignity in front of relatives.
Člověk si má před příbuznýma zachovat důstojnost.
Ow, Sasa!
Au, Saša!
He's revving up the car!
Mácha na to káru!
Uncle Horvat drives me to social services.
Strejda Horvát mě jezdí na sociálku.
He says where's his office?
Říká, kde má tu kancelář?
I can't read your handwriting.
Nemůžu to po tobě přečíst.
On Celetna Street.
V Celetný.
Damn!
Sakra!
What?
Co je?
That's not a proper pub!
To není žádná pořádná hospoda!
Jesus, does it really matter?
Ježíš, to je snad jedno, ne?
It sure does!
No to teda není!
I may be a notary, but I'm not going to be a teetotaler because of it.
Jsem sice notář, ale nehodlám kvůli tomu být abstinent.
But back to the point.
Ale po pořádku.
What if I went there alone?
A co kdybych tam jel sám?
Oh, come on...
Tak to teda pr...
.
.
You know, I've already eaten enough grass.
Víš, to už jsem sežral trávy.
And I'd bring you back sausages.
A jitrnice bych ti přivez.
What about the snout?
A co rypáček?
You'd be lost there without me, right?
Ten byste tam splývali beze mě, viď?
Oh God, this is going to be a disaster.
Ježíšmarja, to bude maló.
Easy, bro, we'll manage.
Klid, brácha, to zvládnem.
Hey, we know how to work in disguise, right?
Heh, pracovat v přestrojení přece umíme, ne?
Really?
Vážně?
We didn't free Ivuska that time, but in those masks we made it right up to her.
Na Ivušku jsme sice tenkrát nevysvobodili, ale v těch maskách jsme se dostali až úplně k ní.
Yeah, you mean when we visited her in the hospital's infectious ward?
Jo, myslíš, jak jsme za ní byli v nemocnici na infekčním?
Yeah!
No!
I promised I'd help you, and Iva doesn't want to go.
Slíbila jsem ti, že ti píchnu, a Iva jet nechce.
You've completely lost your mind.
Ty jsi se to čistá zbláznila.
Great, we'll manage.
Skvělý, to zvládnem.
Dad.
Tati.
Out!
Ven!
Sorry, these clothes probably aren't good enough.
Promiň, ty šaty asi nejsou dost dobrý.
Turn him away too.
Taky ho odvrať.
Now!
No, teraz!
You don't know what it's like at a performance at the National Theatre.
Tiše bevieš, čo je pri predstavení v Národnom divadle.
We went to dad's and he didn't let us in.
Byli jsme u táty a nepustil nás dovnitř.
I'm the winner!
Jsem vítěz!
Winner!
Vítěz!
Lexa, what do you mean winner?
Lexo, jak vítěz?
I didn't say it.
Já jsem to neřekla.
Again?
Zase?
No, I said "that"?
Ne, já jsem řekla "že"?
And that's not the letter.
A to není to písmeno.
Yes it is.
No, to je.
No, it isn't, "that" is allowed.
Ne, není, "že" se může.
Oh, great.
Ó, super.
Should I go then?
Tak já zase půjdu?
No, Ivo, wait.
Ne, Ivo, počkej.
We'll tell you what it was like there.
My ti řekneme, jaký to tam bylo.
Dad and his new wife bought a villa.
Táta si s tou novou tetou koupili vilu.
They must have done well for themselves.
Si nějak zmohli, ne?
Well, she breeds Great Danes.
Hm, ona totiž prodává dogy.
Purebreds.
Značkový.
Really, she had lots of puppies and let me play with them.
Fakt, měla tam spoustu štěňátek a dovolila mi si s nima hrát.
And the wife's okay?
A teta dobrý?
She bought us sundaes, but I didn't really like them.
Hm, koupila nám poháry, ale mně se moc nelíbí.
Sundaes?
Poháry?
Auntie, a sundae, like ice cream.
Teta, pohár, jako zmrzlinu.
Oh right, a sundae.
No jo, pohár.
I like her.
Mně se líbí.
She wears nice snakes.
Nosí pěkný hady.
Grass snakes.
Úžový.
And she had a really great dog.
A měla teda bezva psa.
I know, you already said that.
Já vím, to jste říkali.
No, that's not what I said.
No, to jsem neříkal.
He meant, like, a pig.
On myslel jako prase.
Oh, a pig.
Aha, prase.
What happened?
Co se stalo?
I'm such an idiot.
Já jsem takovej blbec.
Kvetos?
Květoš?
Why does he keep calling me?
Proč mi furt volá?
What was he bragging about?
Čím se chlubil?
How do you know?
Jak to víte?
Zoran only calls when he's bought something new.
Zoran volá, jen když si koupí něco nového.
He just bought a BMW, you know.
Víte, už si koupil bavoráka.
Oh dear, and what about you?
Ajaj, a co vy?
Luckily I didn't mention the brand.
No naštěstí jsem neřekl značku.
Just that my car is better.
Jen to, že to moje auto je lepší.
Marcelka, Zoran has several cars though.
Marcelko, Zoran má ale přece víc aut.
Could he lend me one for the weekend?
Nemohl by mi na víkend jedno půjčit?
Oh, you men.
Ach, vy muži.
I don't know exactly how many cars we have at home right now.
No já přesně nevím, kolik zrovna teď máme aut v domě.
But there's one big one in the yard that we don't use much.
Ale na dvoře stojí jedno takové veliké, co moc nepoužíváme.
And what brand is it?
No a co je to za značku?
I don't know.
To nevím.
It sounded like some kind of shellfish.
Znělo to jako nějaký korýš.
Renault Laguna?
Renault Laguna?
That must be it.
To bude ono.
You really overdid it.
To jsi fakt přehnala.
What are you talking about?
O čem to mluvíš?
Don't play dumb.
Ty nedělej blbou.
Kvetos called me.
Volal mi Květoš.
What happened?
A co se stalo?
Get this -- Kvetos complained that I never told him we have a cousin Simona in Prague.
Tak si představ, že mi Květoš vyčet, že jsem mu neřekl, že máme v Praze sestřenici Šimonu.
No way.
Nepovídej.
She has two kids, she's very poor, and when Kvetos invited her to the pig slaughter, she said she can't come because she can't afford the train.
Má dvě děti, je moc chudá a když ji Květoš pozval na zabíjačku, tak řekla, že nemůže přijet, poněvadž nemá na vlak.
Poor woman.
Chudák ženská.
You really think you're going to ride to Volary with me?
To si vážně myslíš, že se mnou pojedeš do Volar?
Mooching off my relatives?
Vyžírat moje příbuzný?
I could hitchhike.
Tak já bych mohla jet stopem.
But then don't expect me to say nice things about you, cousin.
Ale potom nepočítej, bratránku, s tím, že o tobě budu mluvit v dobrým.
So what time do we leave tomorrow?
Takže v kolik zítra vyrážíme?
Five.
V pět.
That's on me.
To je na mě.
I don't want to.
Když já nechci.
No suit, no pig slaughter.
Není oblek, není zabíjačka.
But why?
Ale proč?
Because I said so.
Protože proto.
At least try it on.
Aspoň si ho zkus.
That's what you said about that nice piece of cloth for my neck too.
No to si říkal ten krásným kusem hadru na krk taky.
Then I found out I was in the Young Pioneers.
Pak jsem zjistil, že jsem v Pionýru.
That was a different era.
To byla jiná doba.
I don't want to!
Nechci!
Fine, I'm calling Kvetos.
Dobře, volám Květošovi.
Hi, Tomas speaking.
Ahoj, Tomáš.
Listen, bad news, the doctor won't make it after all.
Prosím tě, malér, tak pan doktor nakonec nedorazí.
Some flu or something. Hey, no worries, more sausages for us.
No, nějaká chřipajzna nebo co. Hele, nevadí, aspoň bude víc jitrnic na nás.
Sure, let's do it.
No, to si dáme.
I know you're not really calling him.
Já vím, že mu nevoláš.
Stop faking, it doesn't work on me.
Proč si fixlat, nefunguje to na mě.
Give it here.
Dej to sem.
Weasels.
Vytěráči.
Alright, he's feeling a bit better.
Tak ne, nějak se mu ulevilo.
So tomorrow then.
Tak zítra.
Yeah, we're bringing Simona.
Jo, Šimonu bereme.
Bye.
Čau.
Where have you been so long?
Kde jsi byla tak dlouho?
I was in the park.
Byla jsem v parku.
Where?
Kde?
In the park.
V parku.
I thought you said "in a trap."
Já jsem rozuměl v páku.
What's this supposed to be?
Co to má jako bejt?
A dress.
Šaty.
I'm not going.
Nejedu.
At least try it on.
Tak si je aspoň zkus.
You said that about braces too, and then I had to wear them for three years.
To jsi říkal s rovnátkama taky a pak jsem je musela nosit tři roky.
And look how nice and straight your teeth are.
No a jaký máš rovný zoubky?
I'm not going.
Nejedu.
Kvetos's wife Kveta will be tap dancing.
Květošová Květa bude stepovat.
No.
Ne.
Do it for me.
Dělej to pro mě.
I'm not going to make a fool of myself just because you and Kvetos keep trying to one-up each other.
Já tam nebudu šaškovat jenom kvůli tomu, že vy dva s Květošem se furt hecujete.
Ivuska, please.
Ivuško, prosím tě.
No.
Ne.
Ivo, come here.
Ivo, pojď sem.
This is when Kvetos and I went fishing.
Tady jsme byli s Květošem na rybách.
We were seven.
To nám bylo sedm.
And who's got the bigger fish?
A kdo má větší rybu?
He always had the upper hand.
Vždycky měl navrch.
When I had a bike, he already had a moped.
Když já měl kolo, on už měl Pionýra.
When I had a moped, he already had a Zhiguli.
Když já měl Pionýra, on už měl Žigula.
Here we went pony riding together.
Tady jsme spolu šli na poníky.
And who's riding the goat?
A kdo jede na koze?
You.
Ty.
See.
Vidíš.
Dad, I don't even know flamenco.
Tati, já flamenko ani neumím.
You think those hicks will know the difference?
Myslíš, že ti burani to poznají?
Ivo.
Ivo.
Oh, fine.
Ach jo.
But I'm keeping the dress.
Ale ty šaty si nechám.
It was a Hummer!
Humr to byl!
What?
Cože?
The car is called a Hummer.
No to auto se jmenuje Humr.
Are you holding a grenade?
Držíte granát?
No, it's just a keychain.
Ne, to je jen takový přívěšek na klíče.
Zoran bought the car from some soldiers and this was already on it.
Zoran to auto koupil od nějakých vojáků a tohle už na nich bylo.
So he'll lend it to me?
Takže on mi ho půjčí?
He was in a good mood today.
Měl dneska dobrou náladu.
He finally has a bigger yacht than his brother.
Konečně má větší jachtu než bratr.
Marcelka, thank you.
Marcelko, děkuju.
You're a treasure.
Vy jste poklad.
Thank the Somali pirates.
To poděkujte somálským pirátům.
I thought you arranged the car for me.
Já jsem myslela, že jste mi zařídila to auto.
But only with a driver.
Ale jedině s řidičem.
Yeah, he'll give me a driver too.
Jo, on mi k němu dá i řidiče.
He wasn't in that good a mood.
Zase tak dobrou náladu neměl.
But I figured Xenie could come too.
Ale říkala jsem si, že by mohla jet i Xenie.
And who's that again?
A to je zase kdo?
Oh, right.
Jo, aha.
And is the Hummer bigger than the BMW? There'll be a lot of us.
A je ten Humr větší než bavorák, pojede nás totiž hodně.
Zoran sometimes holds board meetings in it, so we'll all fit even if we leave the pool table in.
Zoran v něm občas pořádá výjezdní zasedání svojí správní rady, takže my se tam vejdeme, i když tam necháme ten kulečník.
Hurry up!
Tak dělejte!
Marcelka's already here!
Marcelka už je tady!
One moment!
Moment!
Wait, you need to tie my tie!
Počkej, mně musíš uvázat tu kravatu!
Jesus, stop fussing!
Ježíš, nehemeř se furt!
Tie!
Kravatu!
A Corvette is a car!
Korveta je auto!
Chevrolet!
Chevrolet!
I don't get why you couldn't just get dressed at home.
No vidíš to, já nechápu, proč jste se nemohl převlíct doma?
Right, like I'd want someone to see me like this on the street.
No to zrovna, aby mě takhle někdo viděl na ulici.
Who's going to see you at five in the morning?
Kdo by tě viděl v pět ráno na ulici?
What time do you think the guys get back from the late-night bar?
V kolik myslíš, že kluci chodí z non-stopu?
Does it suit you?
Sluší ti to?
She looks like a princess.
Vypadá jako princezna.
Thank you.
Děkuju.
That green Opel out there, does it belong to someone from the building?
Ten zelený Opel tam venku, je někoho z domu?
Well, Ozzak, you actually look like a human being.
No, Ozzáku, vy vypadáte jako člověk.
It can be taken off.
Jde to sundat.
No suit, no pig slaughter.
Není oblek, není zabíjačka.
Pacovsky, you didn't crash into that Opel, did you?
Pacovský, snad jste nikomu nenabourala Opela?
I didn't crash into it, more like drove over it.
Nenabourala, spíš přejela.
It's really hard to see down from the cabin.
Z kabiny je dolů strašně špatně vidět.
What's this?
Co to je?
If there are any problems, you'll be called away for an inspection of the Blanka tunnel.
Kdyby byly problémy, odvoláte vás na inspekci tunelu Blanka.
Marcelka, you think of everything.
Marcelko, vy myslíte na všechno.
Xenie.
Xenie.
Hello, family.
Nazdar, rodino.
Hello, Simona.
Nazdar, Šimono.
Simona?
Šimono?
So you'll be the one dancing, huh?
Tak ty budeš tancovat, jo?
Smart.
Chytrý.
Wait, what's he doing here?
Moment, co ten tady dělá?
That's Simona's partner Julek.
To je Šimonin druh Julek.
Poor guy, hasn't had a job in three years.
Chudák, už tři roky nezavadil o práci.
Which happens to be true.
Což je náhodou pravda.
Marcelka, can't we go faster?
Marcelko, nemůžeme jet rychleji?
We can't.
Nemůžeme.
The four-wheel drive locked up.
Zabloklo se mi kvatro.
All by itself.
Úplně samo.
I feel like we're driving across a field.
Mám pocit, že jedeme po poli.
We are driving across a field.
Jedeme po poli.
It's really hard to see past the winch.
Přes ten naviják je dolů strašně špatně vidět.
I'll call him that we'll be late.
Zavolám mu, že se zpozdíme.
I'm worried that if they butcher the pig without me, you'll pay for it.
Mám obavu, jestli ho pískou beze mě, tak si to vypijete.
Like, with me it would...
Jako, že se mnou to...
No answer.
Nebere to.
Hey, Kvetos, hi, so...
Hej, Květoši, nazdar, tak...
Hope I didn't wake you, you old sleepyhead.
Snad jsem tě nezbudil, ty starý vospalče.
Yeah, we're on our way, of course we're coming.
Jo, jedeme, jedeme, to víš, že jedeme.
What do you mean, just showing off?
Jak jenom takovej hec?
He can't be serious.
No on snad kecal.
What?
Co?
Kvetos, I cancelled a meeting with a minister because of you.
Květoši, já jsem kvůli tobě zrušil ministra.
And Xenie here gave up her trip to the Canaries.
A tady Xenie mi letěla na Kanáry.
And I took the Corvette!
A já jsem vzal Korvetu!
Kvetos, listen, you started it, right?
Květoši, poslouchej, ty jsi zasvětoval, co?
You're like a little kid.
Jsi jak malej Jarda.
Let me tell you something, listen.
Já ti něco řeknu, poslouchej.
People who lie like that and always want to be the best really piss me off.
Lidi, co takhle kecaj a chtěj bejt za každou cenu nejlepší, mě vážně štvou.
You bet.
To si piš teda.
And don't count on us ever coming.
A nepočítej s tím, že bysme někdy přijeli.
We're not coming.
Nepřijedeme.
And I'm not voting for Ruzena.
A Růženu nevolím.
Nobody is.
Nikdo.
We're not voting for Ruzena.
Růženu nevolíme.
Nobody, got it?
Nikdo, jo?
Nobody.
Nikdo.
Goodbye.
Nazdar.
So the pig slaughter is off.
Takže zabíjačka není.
Now what?
To co?
Just turning around.
Jenom se otáčím.
What kind of person are you, Director?
Co je to za člověk, řediteli?
What do you mean?
Jak to myslíš?
Those people haven't eaten in two days.
Lidi ti dva dny nejedli.
And I've been eating grass, bro!
A já jedl trávu, brácho!
And Horvat lost his deposit!
A Horvát přišel o lukšev!
I was also supposed to have a minister!
Já jsem tiež mal mať ministra!
He went on vacation!
Odišiel na dovolenku!
And has an empty apartment!
A má prázdný byt!
So what the hell am I supposed to do?
A co mám, sakra, jako dělat?
What was that?
Co to bylo?
We ran over something.
Něco jsme přejeli.
Oh God, what?
Proboha co?
I don't know!
Já nevím!
All I can see is that damn winch!
Vidím jen ten zatracenej naviják!
It looked like a wild boar!
Vypadám to jako divočák!
Brake!
Brzda!
Now!
Teď jo!
Keep going!
Pořád!
Is everyone okay?
Jsou všichni v pohodě?
The snout is mine!
Rypáček je můj!
It's mine!
Je můj!
Pacovsky here, Kvetos, hi.
Pacovský, je Květoši, nazdar.
Yeah yeah, we arrived safely.
Jo jo, dojeli jsme v pořádku.
Working hard, working hard, you know, the metro line D doesn't build itself.
No makám, makám, tak to víš, trasa D se sama nepostaví.
Yeah, sure, we should get together sometime.
Jo, to víš, že bysme se mohli vidět, no.
Yeah, you could come visit us in Dejvice.
Jo, že byste přijeli k nám do Dejvic.
Look, Kvetos, rather not, okay?
Hele, Květoši, jako spíš ne, jo?
What, me, bragging?
Cože já, že jsem se vytahoval?
Fine then, come visit.
No tak si přijeď.
Sure, anytime, Saturday.
To no, klidně, v sobotu.
Sure.
Jasně.
Take care, bye.
No tak měj se, ahoj.
What an idiot.
Takovej blbec.
Don't count on Xenie.
S Xenii nepočítejte.